# Samuel Turcotte

Thunder Bay, ON

Email: <a href="mailto:sturcot3@confederationcollege.ca">sturcot3@confederationcollege.ca</a>
LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-turcotte">www.linkedin.com/in/samuel-turcotte</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/sturcott3">https://github.com/sturcott3</a>

### SUMMARY

Mature student transitioning to a second career as software and web developer. Gained a strong foundation in object-oriented programming concepts across a wide range of technologies while studying at Confederation College. Capable of designing, implementing, and deploying simple full-stack applications. Extensive experience working in other fields both in teams and in self-directed settings. Moderate experience leading small teams.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

### Languages

Proficient: C#, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3

Familiar: Java, VB.NET, PHP, SQL (T-SQL and MySQL)

Learning: Ruby, Python

#### Frameworks/Libraries

Proficient: ASP.NET, jQuery, Bootstrap 4

Familiar: React

• Learning: React Native, Node.js, WordPress

#### Software/Tools

Proficient: Visual Studio, VS Code, Chrome Developer tools

• Familiar: GIT (Bash), GitHub, MS SQL Server Management Studio, Microsoft Office

• Learning: Apache, PhpMyAdmin, Docker, Microsoft Project, Microsoft Visio

### **EDUCATION**

## **Confederation College**

September 2018 - April 2021

Thunder Bay, Ontario

- Computer Programmer Ontario College Diploma
- Worked as a peer tutor during semesters 2 and 3.
- · Achieved first class standing in all semesters.

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Web Developer - Freelance

Jan 2021 - Present

Client: StrongMom Health and Wellness Coaching | Thunder Bay, Ontario

- Guided client through joint application design process to develop a modern web presence for their Thunder Bay kinesiology consultancy.
- Researched platforms based on client budget and business requirements and developed a recommendation which was accepted and followed by the client.
- Designed and implemented site content in collaboration with client using WordPress.com.

Aug 2020 - Dec 2020

Outland - (Yataw) | Slate Falls, Ontario

- Planned and executed maintenance tasks associated with remote access construction line camp, including upkeep of water, sewer, and power generation systems.
- Assessed and performed carpentry, plumbing, and electrical repairs on all aspects of the physical plant, including kitchen, guest rooms, common areas, and outdoor walkways.
- Coordinated daily/weekly maintenance tasks and documentation of same with camp manager to facilitate bill-back to client (Valard Construction LP).

Tree Planter May 2008 - Jul 2020

Outland | Various Locations: Ontario, Quebec, and Alberta

 Spring and Summer. Piecework. Skilled labour in the Forestry support industry. Completed ninth season and passed personal goal of 1 million trees planted.

### Web Developer - https://www.oyep.ca/

Sep 2019 - Mar 2020

Outland - (OYEP) | Thunder Bay, Ontario

- Guided non-technical department members through joint application design to create their division's new website according to their business requirements and aesthetic taste.
- Developed the final version of the site using HTML5, Bootstrap 4, jQuery, and PHP.
- Collaborated with Outland's existing hosting provider to deploy the site using their secure FTP server.

## Peer Tutor - Computer Programming

Jan 2019 - Jan 2020

Confederation College - (Student Success) | Thunder Bay, Ontario

- Guided other students through programming exercises, review of past assignments, and other course materials.
- · Courses tutored include:
  - Object Oriented Programming 1-3 (C#, Java)
  - Database Design and SQL (MSSQL, SQL Server Management Studio)
  - Event-Driven Programming (Visual Studio 2017, VB.NET)
  - Software Configuration Management (GIT/GITHUB).

### Construction Worker/Lead Hand

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018

Outland - (Camps) | White River, Ontario

- Performed skilled labour tasks related to the installation of modular bunkhouses and kitchen for a remote access gold mine camp.
- Documented and participated in daily safety meetings to assess and control risks associated with daily tasks.
- Coordinated with site supervisor to organize tasks for myself and 2-3 other workers.

First Cook Aug 2016 – Apr 2017

Outland - (Camps) | Bisset, Manitoba

- Performed a wide range of tasks related to preparing and serving meals in a 24/7 mining camp with average 250 guests.
- Delivered breakfast services as leader of a team of 2-4.
- Prepared meal items for lunch/dinner service at discretion of the Chef.

Head Cook Aug 2014 – Apr 2016

Outland - (Camps) | Various Locations: Ontario, Quebec, Manitoba, and Alberta

- Delivered three meals per day as leader of a small team of 1-3 other cooks in various types of remote camps. Guest numbers ranged from 30 – 100 people per meal.
- Planned menu, tracked inventory, and managed food cost for budgets of up to \$18,000 per week.
- · Prepared financial reports and end of contract summaries of overall food cost.